Guide to the Willard Winfield Rowlee papers, 1905-1923.
Rowlee, Willard Winfield papers, 1905-1923
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Willard Winfield Rowlee papers, 1905-1923.
14-29-234
Willard Winfield Rowlee, 1861-1923.
1.9 cubic ft.
Correspondence, reports, photographs, meeting minutes.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, reports, photographs, and other miscellaneous printed material pertaining to Rowlee's activities at Cornell University and elsewhere.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Cornell University professor and botanist.
Cornell University Class of 1888, PhD. 1893.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, reports, photographs, and other miscellaneous printed material pertaining to Rowlee's activities at Cornell University and elsewhere, including photographs of a botany trip to McLean, New York; a report on the improvement of Dryden Cemetery; faculty communications; minutes of the Alumni Athletic Field Committee pertaining to Alumni Field and Schoellkopf Field House; an athletics and student affairs file concerning expenses and athletics at Cornell; and material relating to the Semi-Centennial Celebration at Cornell. Correspondents include Daniel Alden Reed, Willard Beahan, Franks S. Porter, Henry Schoellkopf, and others.
Also, correspondence, reports, and other material deriving from Rowlee's investigation of balsa wood in the Canal Zone, Costa Rica, Guatemala, Honduras, and Nicaragua, and of the American Balsa Corporation and its evolution into the American International Corporation and the American Balsa Company; also includes specifications for balsa and its characteristics for such uses as life preservers, insulation, and airplane construction
Also, papers relating to the collection and identification of plants, the administration of the Department of Botany at Cornell, and Cornell alumni activities.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Rowlee, Willard Winfield, 1861-1923.; Beahan, Willard.; Porter, Frank S.; Reed, Daniel Alden.; Schoellkopf, Henry.; American Balsa Company.; American Balsa Corporation.; American International Corporation.; Cornell University--Faculty.; Cornell University--Athletics.; Cornell University--Students.; Cornell University--Alumni.; Cornell University--Buildings.; Cornell University. Dept. of Botany.; Cornell University. Semi-Centennial Committee.; Cornell University. Alumni Athletic Field Committee.; Cornell University. Schoellkopf Field House.; Dryden Cemetery (Dryden, N.Y.)
Subjects:
Botany--Study and teaching.; Balsa wood.; Balsa wood craft.; Airplanes--Materials.; Airplanes, wooden.; Cemeteries--New York (State)--Dryden.; Education--New York (State)--Ithaca.; Wood--Canal Zone.; Wood--Costa Rica.; Wood--Guatemala.; Wood--Honduras.; Wood--Nicaragua.; Botanists.; College teachers.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
Includes collections #43-1-36 and #626.
CONTAINER LIST
- 1905-1923 [formerly collection #43-1-36]
  - McLean Trip, Silence Rowlee, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Class Miscellany, 1917-1919 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Cornell materials, 1922-1923 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Cornell materials, 1917-1919; 1922 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Report on Improvement of Dryden Cemetary, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Committee reports re erection of Schoelkopf Memorial building, 1905-1917 (Box 1, Folder 6-7)
- Correspondence; 1909, 1915-1920
  - Davis corrrespondence re peat bogs, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1915-1916 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: Jan.-Mar., 1919 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: Apr.-June, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: July-Sept., 1919 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence: Oct., 1919 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence: Nov., 1919 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence: Dec., 1919 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence: Jan., 1920 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence: Feb., 1920 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence: Mar., 1920 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence: Apr., 1920 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence: May-June, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence: July-Oct., 1920 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence: Nov., 1920 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence: Dec., 1920 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence: Jan., 1921 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence: Feb., 1921 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence: Mar., 1921 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence: Apr., 1921 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence: May, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence: June-Aug., 1921 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence: Sept., 1921 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence: Oct., 1921 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence: Nov., 1921 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence: Dec., 1921 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Correspondence: Jan.-Feb., 1922 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Correspondence: Mar.-Apr., 1922 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Correspondence: May, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Correspondence: June-July, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Correspondence: Sept.-Nov., 1922 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Correspondence: Dec. 1922-Jan. 1924 and n.d., 1922-1924 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Class materials, laboratory handouts, bibliographies, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Miscellany, 1912-1922 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- American Balsa Company, Inc.
  - Correspondence: Jan. 10, 1917-May 9, 1918, 1917-1918 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Correspondence: May 10-May 29, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Correspondence: June 1-June 14, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Correspondence: June 19-July 1, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Correspondence: July 1-Sept. 6, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Correspondence: Sept. 6-Sept. 26, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Correspondence: Sept. 28-Oct. 30, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Correspondence: Nov. 1-Dec. 26, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Correspondence: Jan. 5-Mar. 7, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Correspondence: Mar. 8-Apr. 14, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Correspondence: Apr. 21-July 10, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Correspondence: July 11-Oct. 31, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Correspondence: Nov. 3-Dec. 29, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Correspondence: Jan. 5-Apr. 15, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Correspondence: Apr. 17-June 7, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Correspondence: June 10-June 30, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Correspondence: July 1-July 31, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Correspondence: Aug. 2-Sept. 30, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Correspondence: Oct. 2-Nov. 12, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Correspondence: Nov. 15-Dec. 31, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Correspondence: Jan. 4-Feb. 17, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Correspondence: Mar. 1-May 5, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Correspondence: May 6-Sept. 20, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Correspondence: Sept. 23-Dec. 17, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Correspondence: Jan. 3, 1922-Mar. 28, 1923, 1922-1923 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Correspondence and miscellany, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 69-71)